### **Kumar Abhishek**

## Senior Software Developer | NIT Warangal

kumarabhishek22101997@gmail.com

8092188208

linkedin.com/in/krAbhishek26

https://github.com/krptic07

Tech enthusiast and self-driven Software Developer with **3+ years of experience**, dedicated to driving impactful transformations. Successfully **revamped 3 projects**, resulting in remarkable enhancements in user experience, including a **12-15% surge in customer retention across services and a significant 7-8% increase in D2C account openings**. My commitment lies in delivering top-notch software solutions that consistently surpass expectations.

# Experience

FreeCharge(Axis Bank)

Aug 2021 - Present

#### Senior Software Developer

- Mentored and collaborated with a team of 2 junior developers to **migrate 4** services to a new boilerplate using parcel packaging and a new encryption system.
- Revamped the Redux architecture by implementing Singleton and Abstract Factory design patterns, improving code maintainability, reducing redundancy, and enhancing application scalability.
- Redesigned the UI based on the in-house design system built on Material UI, resulting in a responsive interface with reduced loading times and a 12-15% increase in customer retention, a 7-8% rise in D2C account openings, and enhanced web platform engagement.

#### **Software Developer**

- Created intuitive dashboards for 2 services, amalgamating extensive data into an interactive UI. Before implementation, the team had to navigate multiple sources and services to gather requisite data, resulting in a cumbersome process.
- Led the implementation of a standardized design system using Material UI components; decreased the time needed for UI revisions by 25%, enabling faster project turnaround and improved client satisfaction across the board.

 Tested, debugged, and shipped 10s of 1000s of lines of code to various development teams. This led to 100% bug-free deployment.

Skillzen April 2020 - Aug 2020

#### **SDE Intern**

- Developed and implemented RESTful APIs using Python, Django Rest Framework, and PostgreSQL; these systems enabled seamless access to data on over 10K courses and colleges across India, enhancing educational accessibility.
- Learned to make Database design and API design for microservices, deploying the system on Heroku.
- Collaborated with frontend team on API integration, while also mastering web scraping to deliver diverse website-sourced data to the business team.

# **Key Skills**

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python Markup Languages: HTML, CSS (SCSS, LESS)

Frameworks&Libraries: React, Redux, React Native, Next.js, MaterialUI, ChakraUI,

Bootstrap, Formik, Django, DRM, Node, React Testing Library, Jest

Databases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Software Tools: Git, WebPack, Parcel, Babel, NPM, Figma, Chrome Dev Tools, StoryBook
Other Skills: Responsive Web Design, Server Side Rendering, SEO optimization, Testing &
Debugging, RESTful APIs, Web Performance Optimisation, Agile Methodologies, Problem Solving,
Automation/Scripting, Cross-Browser Compatibility

### Education

#### National Institute of Technology, Warangal

2017-2021

**B.Tech Chemical Engineering** 

#### Delhi Public School, Dhanbad

2002 - 2016

# **Projects**

#### **AdapTest**

Developed a comprehensive **MERN stack** web application enabling users to take adaptive tests, adjusting question quality and difficulty based on user capabilities, culminating in detailed reports highlighting areas for improvement.